Ian Dexter D. Marquez

Linux systems administrator

+31 6 1197 1691 im@iandexter.net https://www.iandexter.net

With 20 years of extensive experience in administering Linux and Unix platforms. Develops and maintains various automation tools for infrastructure management and application deployment. Collaborates with global software development and operations teams in application delivery and support. Certified in Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Microsoft Windows, and ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management.

QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Computing major in Computer Science, 2011

Technological University of the Philippines, Manila

Red Hat Certified Engineer, OCTOBER 2008 (NOT CURRENT)

ITIL v3 Foundation in IT Service Management, JULY 2008

Red Hat Certified Technician, November 2006

Microsoft Certified Professional, May 2006

Trend Micro Certified Security Expert, June 2006

Interests

DevOps, Cloud infrastructure, Big data and Al

Skill areas

- Unix/Linux systems administration (20 years / advanced)
- Infrastructure automation (12 years / proficient)
- Application deployment and support (15 years / advanced)
- Network design, development and administration (5 years / proficient)
- Web design, development and management (3 years / proficient)
- Identity management (2 years / proficient)

Languages

- Bash (20 years / advanced)
- Perl (9 years / proficient)
- PHP (3 years / proficient)
- Python (10 years / proficient)
- SQL (4 years / proficient)
- JavaScript (7 years / proficient)
- Scala (2 years / basic)

Platforms

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux, CentOS, Fedora (20 years / advanced)
- SuSE Linux Enterprise Server (4 years / advanced)
- Ubuntu, Debian (10 years / proficient)
- Sun Solaris, IBM AIX (1 year / basic)
- Microsoft Windows 2003 Server (1 year / basic)

EXPERIENCE

Staff technical solutions engineer

AUGUST 2022 TO PRESENT

Databricks

Acts as technical escalation for frontline support teams, and provides technical guidance and advice to customers in their Databricks journey. Databricks, the data and AI company, helps data teams solve the world's toughest problems. Thousands of organizations – including Comcast, Nationwide and H&M – rely on the Databricks platform to accelerate data-driven innovation.

Backline technical solutions engineer FEBRUARY 2021 TO JULY 2022

Databricks

Platform technical solutions engineer FEBRUARY 2020 TO JANUARY 2021

Databricks

Support and deployment engineer FEBRUARY 2019 TO JANUARY 2020

Bright Computing

Supported customers in managing their high-performance clusters (HPC) using Bright Cluster Manager (BCM). Bright Computing develops high-quality software for deploying and managing high-performance clusters, Kubernetes clusters, and OpenStack private clouds in on-premise data centers and public cloud platforms.

Senior DevOps engineer December 2015 TO December 2018

CompareGlobalGroup

DevOps engineer (part-time) November 2014 to November 2015

Compare Global Group

Accenture, Inc.

Trend Micro, Inc.

Linux system administrator April 2010 to December 2015

Asian Development Bank (under RCG IT, Inc.)

Senior software engineer May 2007 to April 2010

Unix system administrator JANUARY 2007 TO APRIL 2007

Systems engineer April 2006 to January 2007

Linux and web administrator JULY 2004 TO MARCH 2006

Philippine Rice Research Institute

Network administrator

National Irrigation Administration

APRIL 2002 TO JULY 2004

Asian Development Bank (under Cytronics, Inc.)

Community relations / information assistant FEBRUARY 1999 TO MARCH 2002

National Irrigation Administration